

Marcus Burnett

Senior Product Designer Front-end Developer

Info

Portfolio

https://marcus-burnettportfolio.web.app

Email

m.burnett8@outlook.com

Phone

+31619714087

Date of Birth 20/10/1995

Address

Groot-Brittanniestraat 113, Lent, 6663 JC, Netherlands

Languages

- English
- · Dutch (basic)

Skills

- · Complex Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- · Independence
- Teamwork
- Communication

Education

A Level

- · Physics (B)
- Maths (B)
- 3D Design (B)

GCSE

- Physics (A*)
- · Chemistry (A*)
- Biology (A*)
- Art (A*)
- · Maths (A)
- · Technology (A)
- Russian (A)
- English Language (A)
- English Literature (A)
- · Geography (A)

Hobbies

- Football
- Travel
- Gaming

Personal Statement

I am an experienced senior product designer and mid-level front-end developer. I have always been a creative individual with a love of both design and technology, which has been reflected in my career path. I first learnt design, and from the desire to build what I had envisioned, I grew as a developer and got my first job in the industry, working mostly with React and React Native. However, after a while my ability as a designer came to the fore and I began working in a developer/designer hybrid role, creating projects for O2, EE, The Sun and more.

When I moved to the Netherlands, I took on a full-time product design position, and within a year was promoted to senior product designer, catering for 7 agile teams. I am highly skilled at complex problem solving, UI design, prototyping and have been able to utilise my development skills to create realistic prototypes for testing, and teaching a development basics course to my fellow designers.

Employment History

Sendcloud

Aug 2021 - Present

Eindhoven, NL Q

Senior Product Designer

· Responsible for 6 teams within the core domain, as well as the onboarding team

- I was tasked with a complete overhaul of our onboarding experience, leading the project from discovery to delivery, collaborating with users, developers, product managers and key stakeholders across departments to achieve the following results in key aspects of onboarding;
 - Time to ship first parcel: From 54 hrs to just 24 hrs
 - Time to add a payment method: From 7 hrs to just 13 mins
 - · Time to add a brand: From 66 hrs to just 21 hrs
- Revamped our design system to use highly interactive Figma components
- · Taught a development bootcamp for designers to help them work with development in mind
- · Tasked with discovery and design of key, long term company strategies such as smart shipping

Airtime Rewards

Apr 2019 - Aug 2021

Front-End Developer/Product Designer

Manchester, UK 🔾

- Working as part of a 3 person front-end team in a startup, I was given a lot of responsibility
- Creating both web and mobile applications, using React, React Native and Vue.
- Helped to increase our membership base from 250k to 1.3 million by the time I left
- Re-designed and re-built our entire mobile application using a complete brand refresh
- Designed and developed applications for external clients, such as O2, EE and The Sun
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Overhauled our design process to utilise a cloud-based design system and branching

Avios

Aug 2017 - May 2018

Travel Sales Agent

Birchwood, UK 🔾



- This role was heavily incentivised, with a commission scheme based on flight upgrades and addons, such as hotels and car hire
- Despite tough targets, there was not a single month in which I did not meet every single one
- Over time, I became increasingly dissatisfied with goals that actively encouraged poor customer experience (e.g. agents trying to avoid calls that would decrease commission).

Auckland Transport

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016

Customer Service Representative

Auckland, NZ 🔾

- · Worked in the government department responsible for the upkeep of roads and transportation
- Responsible for handling online queries, complaints and emails, triaging each case and either
 providing a quick resolution or forwarding to the appropriate team.
- · Left upon the expiration of my working holiday visa in New Zealand



References

Alex Pamphilon Front-End Team Lead, Airtime Rewards

Email: alexpamphilon@gmail.com

Stuart Kirby Talent Director, Code Nation

Email: stuart.kirby@mac.com

Anita Dagg Sales Team Manager, Avios

Email: anita.dagg@avios.com